Mouhamadou Oumar SALL

+1 (514) 709-1992 mouhamadou.sall@polymtl.ca 4875 Av Dufferin App 505 Montréal (Qc) H3X 2Z2 CANADA

ca.linkedin.com/in/momoumar/

PROFILE

Computer science enthusiast and future engineer in software engineering.

Experience in conception and object-oriented design, programming, testing, debugging.

Able to communicate effectively in English and French and work in a team easily.

Fast learner, resourceful and curious.

EDUCATION

B. ENG. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

2013 - PRESENT

UNIVERSITY OF MONTREAL - ECOLE POLYTECHNIQUE DE MONTREAL (MONTREAL, CANADA)

78/120 credits completed by April 2015.

B. Sc. IN PHYSICS

2010 - 2013

UNIVERSITY OF SAHEL (DAKAR, SÉNÉGAL)

Graduated with high honors.

EXPERIENCE

RESEARCH INTERN 10/2014 - PRESENT

LAB ON MAINTENANCE CONSTRUCTION AND INTELLIGENCE OF SOFTWARE (ECOLE POLYTECHNIQUE DE MONTREAL)

- Deploy, configure and analyze open source continuous integration software (Jenkins and Go) using Amazon Elastic Cloud Computing as server.
- Write python script, using Jenkins REST API, to generate HTML pages for compiling previous builds.

MATHEMATICS AND **C**OMPUTER SCIENCE TUTOR

09/2014 - PRESENT

University of Montreal - Ecole Polytechnique de Montréal (Montreal, Canada)

- Help students solve their exercises.
- Help them better understand the material covered in class.
- Plan study strategies.

PROJECT

DESIGN AND DEVELOPMENT OF AN AUTONOMOUS ROBOT

SPRING 2014

UNIVERSITY OF MONTREAL - ECOLE POLYTECHNIQUE DE MONTRÉAL (MONTREAL, CANADA)

- Assemble and weld the various components of the robot's motherboard.
- Install sensors (sonar, infrared sensor, linetracking sensor) on the robot.
- Program the robot using the C ++ language and AvrLibC library.
- Perform hardware and software testing.

SKILLS

- Object-oriented programming in C ++ / Java / C# / Python / Objective-C & iOS
- Web programming HTML / CSS / Javascript
- Operating System: Linux / Windows / Mac OS
- Development Environment: Visual Studio / Eclipse / Xcode
- Tools: Git / Svn / UML

HONORS - AWARDS

BOURSE UPIR OCTOBER 2014

UNIVERSITY OF MONTREAL - ECOLE POLYTECHNIQUE DE MONTRÉAL (MONTREAL, CANADA)

Grant given to students in order to familiar them with scientific research, by working on a project, under the direction of a professor.

Criterion of selection: Academic excellence - Presentation of the project

AWARD OF EXCELLENCE 2010 - 2013

UNIVERSITY OF SAHEL (DAKAR, SÉNÉGAL)

Underlines academic excellence of students who maintained high grade point average.

HOBBIES

Aviation - Video games - Soccer - Travel.